Joshua D. Lovin

223 Concord TPKE Unit #120, Cambridge, MA 02140 941-376-1615

jdlovin7185@gmail.com

QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY

Creative, effective, high-energy hospitality professional, experienced in motivating teams to deliver consistent customer service and drive profitability. Expert in food & beverage operations in all positions that together create a dynamic work environment. Engaged, adaptive leader, able to empower staff to deliver peak customer service while collaborating with other departments to achieve results.

WORK EXPERIENCE

W Boston, Boston, MA 2019 - 2020

Assistant Restaurant Manager, The Gallery: 13 unionized associates, F&B revenue of \$2M+, ranked in W's top 5 nationally.

- Implemented a beverage control system that reduced cost of service from 30% to 20% by making PAR sheets for each bar to and to keep sufficient stock on hand.
- Reduced expenses to front desk's Comp Gifts and Services budget line by \$500 a week by implementing a process and procedure for "breakfast-included guest(s)," limited the dollar-per-customer amount a guest could use
- Oversaw intimate banquet functions of 10-20 people.
- Assisted in achieving the Marriott Brand Standards Audit score of 88.6 for 2020.
- Exceeded our yearly Guest Satisfaction Survey goal of restaurant service by 3.3 points, earning 67.8.

Marriott Newport Beach Bayview, Newport Beach, CA

2018 - 2019

Food & Beverage Voyager, Marriott's Manager Training Program, at a 250-room hotel with Vista.Kitchen.Bar, a 70-seat restaurant.

- Cross-trained with the banquet department and restaurant management.
- Rotated through front desk, engineering, events, and revenue management, learning how to profit the hotel.
- Adjusted staff schedules according to business needs.
- Organized and purchased liquor and bar supplies according to departmental needs.

LaPlaya Beach & Golf Resort, Naples, FL

2017 - 2018

Room Service Supervisor: Managed a team of 7 associates at a 189-room resort.

- Developed new menus and Standard Operating Procedures for Mini-Bar and In-Room Dining items.
- Inventoried, purchased, and organized supplies for Mini-Bar and In-Room Dining needs.
- Participated in weekly leadership meetings with F&B managers, sharing new ideas and solving problems.
- Effectively addressed guest disputes and charge discrepancies.

LaPlaya Beach & Golf Resort, Naples, FL

2016 - 2017

Food & Beverage Intern

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Science, Resort and Hospitality Management | Florida Gulf Coast University, Ft. Myers, FL CompTIA A+ | Certification in progress

Google IT Support Professional Certificate | Certification in progress

Level 2 Award, Wine and Spirits | Wine & Spirit Education Trust | Florida Wine Academy, Miami, FL

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

National Society of Minorities in Hospitality

Hospitality Management Association